Guide to the Charles Seymour, President of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence and subject files, 1917-1954 1937-1950; 1937-1950; Series I
  - Harvard University, 1937-1950 (Box 78, Folder 680-681)
  - Harvard University, 1937-1950 (Box 79, Folder 682-683)
  - Has - Haz, 1937-1950 (Box 79, Folder 684)
  - Haskins and Sells: auditors, 1937-1948 (Box 79, Folder 685)
  - Havemeyer, Loomis
    See: box 154, folder 1297
  - Hawaii, University of, 1947-1949 (Box 79, Folder 686)
  - Edward W. Hazen Foundation, 1942-1948 (Box 79, Folder 687)
  - He, 1937-1950 (Box 79, Folder 688)
  - Headmaster"s Association, 1938-1939 (Box 79, Folder 689)
  - Health and accident insurance, 1937-1943 (Box 79, Folder 690)
  - Health, Department of, 1937-1950 (Box 80, Folder 691-692)
  - Health, Department of: Mellon gift (Old Dominion Found.) for Div. of Psychiatry and Mental Hygiene, 1945-1949 (Box 80, Folder 693)
  - Health, Department of: question regarding tuberculin test in other universities, 1944-1946 (Box 80, Folder 694)
  - Health, University Board of
    See: box 167, folder 1431
  - Hel - Hen, 1937-1950 (Box 80, Folder 695)
  - Hemingway, Samuel B.
    See: box 155, folder 1307
  - Henderson, Yandell, 1937-1940 (Box 80, Folder 696)
  - Lady Henry Fund, 1937-1950 (Box 80, Folder 697)
  - Her, 1937-1950 (Box 81, Folder 698)
  - Hertz, Bob, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 699)
  - Hi, 1937-1950 (Box 81, Folder 700)
  - Eugene Higgins Trust (Bequest), 1948-1950 (Box 81, Folder 701-703)
  - Eugene Higgins Trust: allocations, 1950-1951 (Box 81, Folder 704)
  - Eugene Higgins Trust: Board of Control, 1950 (Box 81, Folder 705)
  - Eugene Higgins Trust: Conference, 1949-1950 (Box 81, Folder 706)
  - Higher education, costs of
    See: box 56, folder 493-495
  - Highway Traffic, Bureau of
    See: box 35, folder 303-304
  - Hillel Foundation, 1945-1950 (Box 81, Folder 707)
  - Hillhouse Estate, 1942-1943 (Box 82, Folder 708)
  - Hindemith, Paul
    See: box 114, folder 974
  - Hiring practices
    See: box 68, folder 593
  - History, Department of, 1937-1950 (Box 82, Folder 709-712)
  - History, Department of: K. Asakawa, 1948-1949 (Box 82, Folder 713)
  - History, Department of: Guide to Current Diplomatic Problems, 1941-1943 (Box 82, Folder 714)
  - History, Department of: Ralph Turner, 1944 (Box 82, Folder 715)
  - History of Art, Department of, 1940-1950 (Box 83, Folder 716)
  - Ho, 1938-1950 (Box 83, Folder 717)
  - Hodza, Milan, 1942 (Box 83, Folder 718)
  - Hol - Hop, 1937-1950 (Box 83, Folder 719-720)
  - Holcombe, John Marshall Jr.
    See: box 5, folder 41
  - Holden, Reuben A., Assistant to the President, 1947-1949 (Box 83, Folder 721)
  - Honorary Degrees Committee
    See: box 176, folder 1516-1520
  - Hor - Hs, 1937-1950 (Box 83, Folder 722-723)
  - Housing Bureau, 1945-1949 (Box 83, Folder 724)
  - Housing Committee
    See: box 147, folder 1237
  - Housing facilities, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 725)
  - Housing program, 1938-1941 (Box 83, Folder 726)
  - Housing projects: Grosvenor Atterburg, 1937-1938, 1944 (Box 83, Folder 727)
  - Howe, Mrs. Lavinia Verrill (Lucy L.Verrill), 1940-1941 (Box 83, Folder 728)
  - Howland Memorial Prize, 1937-1949 (Box 84, Folder 729-730)
  - Hoyt, James Humphrey, Memorial Fund, 1939-1950 (Box 84, Folder 731)
  - Hub - Hum, 1937-1950 (Box 84, Folder 732)
  - Human Welfare Group, 1929 (Box 84, Folder 733)
  - Humanities, Division of the, 1946-1950 (Box 84, Folder 734)
  - Humanities, Division of the, Committee
    See: box 163, folder 1382
  - Hume, Dr. Edward H., 1937, 1940 (Box 84, Folder 735)
  - Hun - Hy, 1937-1950 (Box 84, Folder 736-737)
  - I, 1937-1950 (Box 85, Folder 738-742)
  - Inaugural Address: comments and requests, 1937-1939 (Box 86, Folder 743)
  - Inauguration, 1937 (Box 86, Folder 744)
  - Inauguration: telegrams and letters from alumni associations and clubs, and other institutions and individuals, 1937 (Box 86, Folder 745)
  - Inauguration: telegrams and letters from class secretaries, undated (Box 86, Folder 746)
  - Income Stabilization for a Developing Democracy, undated (Box 86, Folder 747)
  - Index Society, 1941 (Box 86, Folder 748)
  - Indic and Far Eastern Language & Literature, 1946-1947 (Box 86, Folder 749)
    See also: box 69, folder 597
  - Ingham University - Mrs. Humphrey, 1943 (Box 86, Folder 749a)
  - Institute for Advanced Studies, 1938-1950 (Box 86, Folder 750)
  - Institute of Far Eastern Languages [formerly Institute of Chinese Language and Culture], 1945-1949 (Box 86, Folder 751)
  - Institute of Human Relations
    See: box 107, folder 907
  - Institute of International Education, 1937-1950 (Box 86, Folder 752)
  - Institute of International Education, 1937-1950 (Box 87, Folder 753)
  - Institute of International Legal Research: International Law, 1938-1939 (Box 87, Folder 754)
  - Institute of International Studies, 1934-1949 (Box 87, Folder 755-757)
  - Institute of International Studies: Advisory Council, 1944-1950 (Box 87, Folder 758)
  - Institute of International Studies: Advisory Council, 1944-1950 (Box 88, Folder 759)
  - Institute of International Studies: Anglo-American relations in the post-war world, 1942-1944 (Box 88, Folder 760-763)
  - Institute of International Studies: Dumbarton Oaks Plan, 1944 (Box 88, Folder 764)
  - Institute of International Studies: Rockefeller Foundation grants, Carnegie Corporation applications, 1943-1950 (Box 89, Folder 765)
  - Institute of Nutrition, 1938-1948 (Box 89, Folder 766)
  - Institute of Occupational Medicine and Hygiene
    See: box 107, folder 911-913
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1937-1948 (Box 89, Folder 766a)
  - Inter-College Athletics
  - Inter-Fraternity Council
    See: box 155, folder 1298
  - International Student Association, 1938-1939 (Box 89, Folder 767)
  - International Student Service of the U.S., 1938-1943 (Box 89, Folder 768)
  - Investment portfolio
    See: box 152, folder 1283
  - Invitations declined, 1937, 1943, 1947 (Box 89, Folder 769)
  - J, 1937-1950 (Box 90, Folder 770-771)
  - Japanese Collections: Yale Association of Japan, 1937-1938 (Box 90, Folder 772)
  - Jennings, Miss Annie B. (c.s. address at Fairfield 1935 July 4), 1938-1940 (Box 90, Folder 773)
  - Jo, 1937-1950 (Box 90, Folder 774)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1937-1950 (Box 90, Folder 775)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1937-1939 (Box 90, Folder 776)
  - Johnson, F.B.
    See: box 35, folder 306
  - Jon, 1937-1950 (Box 90, Folder 777)
  - Jonathan Edwards College
  - Judaica research
    See: box 98, folder 839
  - Junior Promenade, 1937-1941 (Box 90, Folder 778)
  - Ka, 1937-1950 (Box 90, Folder 779)
  - Kahn, Dr. Eugen
    See: box 111, folder 941
  - Kane, Grenville (library of)
    See: box 100, folder 848
  - Ke, 1937-1950 (Box 90, Folder 780)
  - Ken, 1937-1950 (Box 91, Folder 781)
  - Kennedy, Prof. Raymond, 1950 (Box 91, Folder 782)
  - Ki, 1937-1950 (Box 91, Folder 783)
  - Kiphuth, R.J.H.
    See: box 23, folder 190
  - Kl - Ko, 1937-1950 (Box 91, Folder 784-785)
  - Klebs, Dr. Arnold C.
    See: box 108, folder 919
  - Knollenberg, Bernhard
    See: box 100, folder 849
  - Kr - Ky, 1937-1950 (Box 91, Folder 786-787)
  - Lab - Lan, 1937-1950 (Box 92, Folder 788)
  - Labor Committee
    See: box 131, folder 1102
  - Labor-Management Center, 1945-1950 (Box 92, Folder 789-790)
  - Labor-Management Center: policy committee, 1945-1948 (Box 92, Folder 791)
  - Labor-Management Center: publications, 1946-1948 (Box 92, Folder 792)
  - Labor Relations - Chiliastri and Pastro case
  - Labor Relations Committee
    See: box 177, folder 1521
  - Labor Studies, Division of [in Graduate School and Institute of Human Relations], 1942-1943 (Box 92, Folder 793)
  - Lampman, Leonard Bronk: bequest, 1939-1940 (Box 92, Folder 794)
  - Lane, Clayton, 1946 (Box 92, Folder 795)
  - Lap - Laz, 1937-1950 (Box 92, Folder 796)
  - Lasswell, Harold
  - L'Atelier (French cultural organization), 1941-1942 (Box 93, Folder 797)
  - Latin-American Studies: miscellaneous correspondence re: plans for, 1941-1943 (Box 93, Folder 798)
  - Law Journal
    See: box 97, folder 826
  - Law School Committee
    See: box 163, folder 1387
  - Law School: bulletins, 1938-1939, 1947-1948 (Box 93, Folder 799)
  - Law School: Committee of Inquiry, 1948 (Box 93, Folder 800)
  - Law School: Corporation meeting, material for, 1949 January 8 (Box 93, Folder 801)
  - Law School: deanship, 1939-1946 (Box 93, Folder 802-804)
  - Law School: faculty, appointments, promotions, etc., 1937-1950 (Box 94, Folder 805-808)
  - Law School: faculty, appointment of Lasswell and Emerson, 1945-1946 (Box 94, Folder 809)
  - Law School: faculty, Chicago Tribune cartoon, 1939 (Box 94, Folder 810)
  - Law School: general, 1937-1950 (Box 94, Folder 811)
  - Law School: general, 1937-1950 (Box 95, Folder 812-816)
  - Law School: Prof. Fowler Harper, 1948 (Box 96, Folder 817)
  - Law School: Harvard and Yale Law School combined courses, 1937-1939 (Box 96, Folder 818)
  - Law School: Law Librarian, 1945 (Box 96, Folder 819)
  - Law School: Law Library (book purchase fund - Hoober gift), 1939-1942 (Box 96, Folder 820)
  - Law School: Underhill Moore, 1937-1945 (Box 96, Folder 821)
  - Law School: "National Policy for the Oil Industry" - Rostow, 1948 (Box 96, Folder 822)
  - Law School: special appointments, 1945-1946 (Box 96, Folder 823)
  - Law School: summer session, 1941 (Box 96, Folder 824)
  - Law School: tuition, fellowships, scholarships, loan fund, etc., 1938-1950 (Box 96, Folder 825)
  - Law School: Yale Law Journal, 1938-1950 (Box 97, Folder 826)
  - Law School: Yale Law School Association, 1943-1950 (Box 97, Folder 827)
  - Law School: Yale Law School Student Association, Committee to Inquire Into Tuition Increase, 1949-1950 (Box 97, Folder 828)
  - Law School Committee
    See: box 54, folder 470
  - Lea - Lem, 1937-1950 (Box 97, Folder 829)
  - Learned Societies: meetings at Yale, 1937-1950 (Box 97, Folder 830)
  - Leaves of absence, 1938-1945 (Box 97, Folder 831)
  - Lecture Committee
    See: box 177, folder 1522
  - Len - Ley, 1937-1950 (Box 97, Folder 832)
  - Lewis, Wilmarth S., 1937-1949 (Box 97, Folder 833)
  - Li, 1937-1950 (Box 98, Folder 834-835)
  - Liberal Arts, 1942-1944 (Box 98, Folder 836)
  - Liberal Arts Lecture Series - 1943 Nov, 1943-1944 (Box 98, Folder 837)
  - Liberal Studies Committee
    See: box 177, folder 1523
  - Libraries
    See: box 158, folder 1339
  - Library: Bollingen Prize in poetry, 1950 (Box 98, Folder 838)
  - Library Committee
    See: box 164, folder 1389
  - Library: Committee on Judaica Research, Rabinowitz Foundation, 1944-1949 (Box 98, Folder 839)
  - Library: Council on Library and Museums, 1944-1950 (Box 98, Folder 840)
  - Library: general, 1937-1950 (Box 98, Folder 841)
  - Library: general, 1937-1950 (Box 99, Folder 842-846)
  - Library: general, 1937-1950 (Box 100, Folder 847)
  - Library: Grenville Kane [library of], 1944 (Box 100, Folder 848)
  - Library: Bernhard Knollenberg, 1940-1946 (Box 100, Folder 849)
  - Library: Librarianship, successor to Mr. Keogh, 1937-1938 (Box 100, Folder 850)
  - Library: Librarianship, successor to Mr. Knollenberg, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 851)
  - Library: position classification and pay plan, 1947-1948 (Box 100, Folder 852)
  - Library: war materials, undated (Box 100, Folder 853)
  - Library: Yale Library Associates, 1937-1950 (Box 100, Folder 854)
  - Library and Museums Committee
    See: box 54, folder 471
  - Library Committee
    See: box 177, folder 1524
  - Listening Posts
    See: box 165, folder 1404
  - Lo, 1937-1950 (Box 100, Folder 855-856)
  - Lohmann, Carl A., 1937-1948 (Box 101, Folder 857)
  - Loomis, James Lee, 1940-1948 (Box 101, Folder 858)
  - Loram, Prof. Charles T., 1937-1941 (Box 101, Folder 859)
  - Lu - Ly, 1937-1950 (Box 101, Folder 860)
  - Loram"s Yale-North Carolina-Hampton Conference at Yale, 1937 October 20-26 (Box 101, Folder 861)
  - Mab - Mag, 1937-1950 (Box 101, Folder 862)
  - Mah - Map, 1937-1950 (Box 101, Folder 863)
  - Mallory, William Neely (memorial plans etc.), 1945, 1949 (Box 101, Folder 864)
  - Mar, 1937-1950 (Box 101, Folder 865)
  - Mar, 1937-1950 (Box 102, Folder 866)
  - Marshall Plan, Committee for the, 1947-1949 (Box 102, Folder 867-868)
  - Mas - Maz, 1937-1950 (Box 102, Folder 869)
  - Mathematics, Department of, 1939-1949 (Box 102, Folder 870)
  - Mathematics, Department of, 1939-1949 (Box 103, Folder 871)
  - Matriculation, 1937-1941 (Box 103, Folder 872)
  - May, Mark A.
    See: box 108, folder 921
  - McA - McC, 1937-1950 (Box 103, Folder 873)
  - McConaughy, Gov. James L., 1938-1948 (Box 103, Folder 874)
  - McCormick, Vance C., 1938-1946 (Box 103, Folder 875)
  - McD - McI, 1937-1950 (Box 103, Folder 876)
  - MacGregor, J. Kenneth, 1940 (Box 103, Folder 877)
  - McK - McV, 1937-1950 (Box 103, Folder 878)
  - McLaughlin Prize, 1938, 1945 (Box 103, Folder 879)
  - McMillen, Drury A., 1942-1946 (Box 104, Folder 880)
  - Mea - Mey, 1937-1950 (Box 104, Folder 881)
  - Medical Affairs, Division of Committee
    See: box 163, folder 1383
  - Medical School, 1937-1950 (Box 104, Folder 882-885)
  - Medical School, 1937-1950 (Box 105, Folder 886-890)
  - Medical School, 1937-1950 (Box 106, Folder 891)
  - Medical School: Aeromedical Research Unit - Dr. Fulton, 1945-1946 (Box 106, Folder 892)
  - Medical School: Anatomy, Department of, 1940-1950 (Box 106, Folder 893)
  - Medical School: Child Welfare Research Fund, 1937-1941 (Box 106, Folder 894)
  - Medical School: Committee on the Deanship and the Study of the Administrative Organization of the School of Medicine, 1945-1946 (Box 106, Folder 895)
  - Medical School: Committee on the Professorship of Pathology, 1948-1950 (Box 106, Folder 896)
  - Medical School: Committee on the Professorship of Pharmacology, 1938, 1940 (Box 106, Folder 897)
  - Medical School: Committee on Program and Policy: minutes, 1944-1945 (Box 106, Folder 898)
  - Medical School: Committee to Study the Future of the Department of Public Health, 1944-1945 (Box 106, Folder 899)
  - Medical School: Deanship, 1939-1940, 1946-1947 (Box 106, Folder 900-901)
  - Medical School: dental pathology, Rockefeller Foundation and Carnegie Corporation gift for, 1937-1938 (Box 106, Folder 902)
  - Medical School: fluid research fund - Rockefeller Fund, 1938 (Box 106, Folder 903)
  - Medical School: Alan Gregg, 1940 (Box 106, Folder 904)
  - Medical. School: haemolytic streptococci, program for research on, 1939 April (Box 106, Folder 905)
  - Medical School: housing project [proposed], 1939-1941 (Box 107, Folder 906)
  - Medical School: Institute of Human Relations, 1937-1950 (Box 107, Folder 907)
  - Medical School: Institute of Human Relations: automobile driver research project, 1938-1939 (Box 107, Folder 908)
  - Medical School: Institute of Human Relations: executive committee, 1937-1938 (Box 107, Folder 909)
  - Medical School: Institute of Human Relations: history, 1922-1949 (Box 107, Folder 910)
  - Medical School: Institute of Occupational Medicine and Hygiene, 1945-1949 (Box 107, Folder 911-913)
  - Medical School: Library, 1939-1943 (Box 107, Folder 914)
  - Medical School: Library, 1939-1943 (Box 108, Folder 915)
  - Medical School: Library: Charles A. Coffin Memorial Fund, 1941-1948 (Box 108, Folder 916)
  - Medical School: Library, Harvey Cushing, 1937-1946 (Box 108, Folder 917)
  - Medical School: Library, Cushing Library Advisory Board, 1939-1949 (Box 108, Folder 918)
  - Medical School: Library, Dr. Arnold C. Klebs, 1938-1947 (Box 108, Folder 919)
  - Medical School: Life Insurance Medical Research Fund (Dr. C.N.H. Long), 1945 (Box 108, Folder 920)
  - Medical School: Mark A. May, 1937-1950 (Box 108, Folder 921)
  - Medical School: Medical Affairs, Director of, George B. Darling, 1946-1950 (Box 108, Folder 922)
  - Medical School: Medical Affairs, Director of, George B. Darling Atlantic Monthly article, 1950 (Box 108, Folder 923)
  - Medical School: Medical Affairs, Division of, 1946-1950 (Box 108, Folder 924)
  - Medical School: Medical Affairs, review of (1946-1950) (Box 108, Folder 925)
  - Medical School: New Haven Hospital, 1937-1950 (Box 109, Folder 926-928)
  - Medical School: New Haven Hospital-Medical School Relations [joint committee], 1941-1946 (Box 109, Folder 929-931)
  - Medical School: New Haven Hospital-Medical School Relations [joint committee]: agreements, 1945 (Box 110, Folder 932)
  - Medical School: nutrient value of soybeans - Dr. Burkholder, 1943-1944 (Box 110, Folder 933)
  - Medical School: nutrition, 1945-1947 (Box 110, Folder 934)
  - Medical School: pamphlets, 1922-1943 (Box 110, Folder 935)
  - Medical School: Physiological Chemistry, Department of, 1937-1939 (Box 111, Folder 936)
  - Medical School: Physiological Chemistry and Pharmacology, Department of, 1939-1950 (Box 111, Folder 937)
  - Medical School: Physiology, Department of, 1939-1950 (Box 111, Folder 938)
  - Medical School: Preventive Medicine [Dr. John R. Paul], 1940-1949 (Box 111, Folder 939)
  - Medical School: Psychiatry and Mental Hygiene, Department of, 1937-1950 (Box 111, Folder 940)
  - Medical School: Psychiatry and Mental Hygiene, Department of: Dr. Eugen Kahn, 1946-1950 (Box 111, Folder 941)
  - Medical School: Public Health, Department of: chairmanship, 1944-1950 (Box 111, Folder 942)
  - Medical School: Public Health Report: extra copies, 1944 (Box 111, Folder 943)
  - Medical School: public relations material
    See: box 134, folder 1131
  - Medical School: statements, speeches, 1943 (Box 111, Folder 944)
  - Medical School: Surgery, Department of, Section of Oncology, U.S. Public Health Service [Robert E. Hunter], 1947-1949 (Box 111, Folder 945)
  - Medical School: vitamin B complex, study of, with the mouse as an experimental animal - vitamin content of important plant foods: Cowgill, 1942-1944 (Box 111, Folder 946)
  - Medical School: vitamins, researches on the physiology of: Rockefeller Foundation grant to Prof. Cowgill, 1938 (Box 111, Folder 947)
  - Medical School Endowment
    See: box 55, folder 488
  - Memorial Day, 1939-1950 (Box 111, Folder 948)
  - Memorial Day parade, 1950 (Box 111, Folder 949)
  - Memorials Committee
    See: box 177, folder 1525
  - Mendell, Clarence W., 1938-1946 (Box 112, Folder 950)
    See also: box 23, folder 191
  - Mer - Mey, 1937-1950 (Box 112, Folder 951-952)
  - Mercer Fund, 1938-1944, 1949 (Box 112, Folder 953)
  - Mic - Mix, 1937-1950 (Box 112, Folder 954-956)
  - Microbiology, Department of, 1949-1950 (Box 112, Folder 957)
  - Miles, Dr. Walter R.: physiological optics as related to visual aids, 1943-1944 (Box 112, Folder 958)
  - Military and Naval Affairs Committee
    See: box 164, folder 1390
  - Military Science and Tactics
    See: box 138, folder 1167-1169
  - Miller, 1937-1950 (Box 113, Folder 959)
  - Miller, Francis P., Bell, Ulrich, 1940-1942 (Box 113, Folder 960)
  - Miller, Ogden D.
    See: box 10, folder 83 See: box 23, folder 192
  - Mob - Moo, 1937-1950 (Box 113, Folder 961)
  - Moore, Mrs. Paul
    See: box 18, folder 152
  - Mor - Mow, 1937-1950 (Box 113, Folder 962-963)
  - Morse, Jarvis M., 1941-1950 (Box 113, Folder 964)
  - Mory"s Association, 1938-1950 (Box 113, Folder 965)
  - Mue - Mun, 1937-1950 (Box 113, Folder 966)
  - Mur - My, 1937-1950 (Box 113, Folder 967)
  - Mur - My, 1937-1950 (Box 114, Folder 968)
  - Murdock Incident and letters of protest, 1950 (Box 114, Folder 969)
  - Murphy, Fred T., 1937-1941 (Box 114, Folder 970)
  - Music, Department of, 1940 (Box 114, Folder 971)
  - Music School, 1938-1950 (Box 114, Folder 972-973)
  - Music School Committee
    See: box 164, folder 1391
  - Music School: Paul Hindemith, 1940-1941 (Box 114, Folder 974)
  - Music School: Stoeckel Estate Norfolk Music School, 1939-1950 (Box 114, Folder 975)
  - Musser, John M., 1938-1950 (Box 114, Folder 976)
  - Mutual Fund proposal, 1949 (Box 114, Folder 977)
  - Myers, George Hewitt, 1938-1949 (Box 114, Folder 978)
  - Na - Ne, 1937-1950 (Box 115, Folder 979-984)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1937-1948 (Box 116, Folder 985)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene, 1938-1949 (Box 116, Folder 986-987)
  - National Fund for Medical Education, 1948-1950 (Box 116, Folder 988-989)
  - National Institute of Public Affairs, 1937-1939, 1945 (Box 116, Folder 990)
  - National Municipal League, 1940-1948 (Box 116, Folder 991)
  - "National Policy for the Oil Industry" - Rostow
    See: box 96, folder 822
  - National Research Council, 1938-1950 (Box 116, Folder 992)
  - National Research Council, 1938-1950 (Box 117, Folder 993)
  - National Tuberculosis Association, 1939-1950 (Box 117, Folder 994)
  - National Yale Alumni Placement Service, 1941-1947 (Box 117, Folder 995)
    See also: box 7, folder 59
  - National Yale Alumni Placement Service, 1941-1947 (Box 117, Folder 996)
  - National Youth Administration
    See: box 33, folder 294
  - Natural Preserve
    See: box 71, folder 612
  - The Nature and Aims of General Education, undated (Box 117, Folder 997)
  - Near Eastern Languages and Literatures, Department of [formerly Oriental Studies], 1937-1949 (Box 117, Folder 998)
  - Negro students: problem regarding, 1941-1946 (Box 117, Folder 999)
  - New, 1937-1950 (Box 118, Folder 1000-1004)
  - Newcomers" Club of Yale University, 1947-1948 (Box 118, Folder 1005)
  - New England Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1937-1950 (Box 118, Folder 1006)
  - New Haven, 1937-1950 (Box 118, Folder 1007)
  - New Haven, 1937-1950 (Box 119, Folder 1008-1011)
  - New Haven City Planning Commission, 1941-1946 (Box 119, Folder 1012)
  - New Haven Community Chest, 1937-1949 (Box 119, Folder 1013)
  - New Haven Hospital
    See: box 109, folder 926-931 See: box 110, folder 932
  - New Haven Orchestra Association, 1937-1950 (Box 119, Folder 1014)
  - New Haven Tercentenary Festival: general committee, 1937-1939 (Box 120, Folder 1015)
  - New Haven Tercentenary Festival: Yale committee, 1937-1938 (Box 121, Folder 1016)
  - New York Herald Tribune Forum, 1937-1950 (Box 121, Folder 1017)
  - New York Times, 1937-1950 (Box 121, Folder 1018)
  - New York University, 1938-1950 (Box 121, Folder 1019)
  - New York World's Fair (1939), 1937-1939 (Box 121, Folder 1020)
  - New York Yale Club: freshman prizes
    See: box 73, folder 634
  - New York World's Fair (1940), 1939-1940 (Box 120, Folder 1021)
  - News Bureau
    See: box 133, folder 1125
  - Ni - Ny, 1937-1950 (Box 120, Folder 1022-1023)
  - Nicoll, Allardyce
    See: box 61, folder 532
  - Noble, Nathaniel [Episcopal Chaplain], 1937 (Box 120, Folder 1024)
  - Northrop, Prof. F.S.C., 1940-1946 (Box 121, Folder 1025)
  - Noyes, Edward Simpson
  - Noyes, Rev. Morgan Phelps, 1945-1949 (Box 121, Folder 1026)
  - Nursing School, 1937-1950 (Box 121, Folder 1027-1030)
  - Nursing School: Alumnae Association, 1940-1948 (Box 121, Folder 1031)
  - Nursing School: minutes, 1945-1950 (Box 121, Folder 1032)
  - Nursing School: deanship, 1943-1944 (Box 122, Folder 1033)
  - Nursing School: dormitory needs, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 1034)
  - Nursing School: public relations material
  - Nutrition
    See: box 110, folder 934 See: box 89, folder 766
  - Nutrition Foundation, Inc., 1943-1949 (Box 122, Folder 1035)
  - Nyman R. Carter
    See: box 126, folder 1067
  - Oa - Ok, 1937-1950 (Box 122, Folder 1036)
  - Observatory: correspondence leading to the selection of the South African site: correspondence with the University of the Witwatersrand, 1922-1943 (Box 122, Folder 1037)
  - Observatory: joint operation of the southern station by the observatories of Columbia and Yale, undated (Box 122, Folder 1038)
  - 0l - Ox, 1937-1950 (Box 122, Folder 1039-1040)
  - Old Dominion Foundation, 1949 (Box 122, Folder 1041)
  - Olds, Irving S., 1940-1950 (Box 123, Folder 1042)
  - Opera project
    See: box 75, folder 656
  - Osgood, Dr. Cornelius
    See: box 125, folder 1059